Register of the Stefan Jędrychowski papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Stefan Jędrychowski papers
1941-1994
95030
Hoover Institution Archives
4 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box (3.3 linear feet)
Interview transcripts, speeches and writings, correspondence, and photographs relating to governmental administration, economic planning, and foreign policy in Poland.
Jędrychowski, Stefan.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1995.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Stefan Jędrychowski (1910-1996) was a Polish economist and politician who served in many high-ranking offices of the Polish People's Republic. He joined the communist party in Wilno, where he was born and educated, before World War II, becoming a member of the Soviet Communist Party during the war. In the 1940s, Jędrychowski was a member of the Polish Committee of National Liberation (PKWN), representing the committee in Moscow and France and then serving in the national unity government as the Minister of Navigation and Foreign Trade. In Poland he served as the vice president of the Rada Ministrów from 1951 to 1956; president of the Komisja Planowania from 1956 to 1968; Minister of Foreign Affairs from 1968 to 1971; and Minister of Finance from 1971 to 1974. He was also a member of the Central Committee of the Polish United Workers' Party in the 1950s and 1960s.
Scope and Content of Collection
The papers of Stefan Jędrychowski consist of interview transcripts, speeches and writings, correspondence, and photographs relating to governmental administration, economic planning, and foreign policy in Poland. The collection is divided into two series, both arranged chronologically. The documentary and photographic evidence which Jędrychowski preserved about his governmental activity in communist Poland provides a window into the highest levels of party life during the post-war decades and Poland's place in the orbit of communist states.
The Speeches, Interviews, and Writings series, containing speeches, interviews, planning documents and other writings by Jędrychowski, is strongest in the earliest period of his political and governmental activity during the late 1940s and early 1950s. The transcript of an extensive interview of Jędrychowski conducted in the early 1990s is at the end of this series and forms a useful guide to the original documents.
The Photographs series reflect the full range of Jędrychowski's public life from the 1940s into the 1980s. Nearly all were produced by professional, official government photographers and primarily document Jędrychowski's participation in official visits, ceremonies, and meetings in Poland and abroad as a representative of the Polish government. This part of the collection is richest, therefore, from the mid-1950s to the early 1970s. Frequently Jędrychowski is not the main participant in an event, being a listener or observer of the primary participant or action. He annotated extensively on the back of most of the photographs. The descriptions in this finding aid are summaries that will help guide researchers to particular photographs or year ranges, but they are not exhaustive in terms of what a researcher will be able to identify about a photograph when consulting it, nor is it an exhaustive, photograph-by-photograph, register.
Poland--Politics and government--1945-1980.; Poland--Economic policy--1945-1981.; Poland--Foreign relations--1945-1989.; Statesmen--Poland.
- Speeches, Interviews, Writings, 1946-1994
  Scope and Contents note
  The speeches, drafts of articles and other writings, and planning documents from the 1940s are originals for which Jędrychowski created a complete numbered title inventory. Beginning in 1950, the documents are primarily photocopies of his original manuscripts and typescripts. These photocopies have a new numbering system, but this range of numbers is not complete and no title inventory was supplied by Jędrychowski. Original documents and extensive photocopies from originals have been described at the folder level using Jędrychowski’s own Polish title or an English summary title of contents. Smaller, and non-original documents, are arranged chronologically. Like the earlier range of documents from the late 1940s, which have full title access in the Scope and Contents notes of each folder, these are planning notes, drafts of speeches, articles, and other writings which Jędrychowski created in the early 1950s.
  When a numbered inventory had been made by Jędrychowski, this system is kept, so that there are a few documents which are in effect his memories about the late 1940s and 1950s, produced in the 1980s, which are filed alongside the documents of the period itself. The early 1990s interviews looking back over his entire career, however, relate to all events and writings of his professional life, so they are filed at the time of their creation.
  - 1946 (numbers 1-9) (Box-folder 1: 1)
    1) Z problematyki handlu zagranicznego. (IX 1946); 2) Tezy do referatu o organizacji handlu zagranicznego. (IX 1946); 3) (X 1946); 4) Na drodze do polskiego eksportu. (I 1946); 5) Przemowienie na Zjezdzie Kierownikow Placowek Zagranicznych Ministerstwa Zeglugi i handlu Zagranicznego dotyczace strategii gospodarczej. (XII 1946); 6) Nowa Umowa handlowa polsko-radziecka o wymianie gospodarczej. (1946); 7) Przemowienie wygloszone na posiedzeniu z dyrektorem generalnym UNRRA. (1946); 8) Tezy o polityce handlu zagranicznego. (1946); 9) Wybory 1946. Strategia polityczna. (I 1946).
  - 1947 (numbers 10-14) (Box-folder 1: 2)
    10) Na drodze rozwoju polskiego handlu zagranicznego. (1947); 11) Przemowienie na plenarnym posiedzeniu KC PPR o strategii gospodarczej. ( 13-14. IV .1947); 12) Angielska droga do socjalizmu, czy kapitalizm panstwowy. (1947); 13) Przemowienie wygloszone na zjezdzie Zwiazku Walki Mlodych o pakcie o wspolpracy i jednosci dzialania PPR i PPS. (1948); 14) O znaczeniu niektorych roznic w ocenie biezacej polityki gospodarczej. (Artykul do "Nowych Drog" Nr.4, VII 1947).
  - 1947 (numbers 15-19) (Box-folder 1: 3)
    Scope and contents note
    15) Zmiany w swiecie imperialistycznym. (XII 1947); 16) O imperializmie. (XII 1947); 17) Walka o wolnosc nauki, czy o utrzymanie starego porzadku; 18) Notatka informacyjna o sprawie propagandy anglosaskiej. (1947); 19) Przemowienie na Zjezdzie Zw. Zaw. Wlokniarzy. (XI 1947).
  - 1947 (numbers 20-23, 25) (Box-folder 1: 4)
    20) Przemowienie na rocznice Rewolucji Pazdziernikowej. (XI 1947); 21) Przemowienie na swieto Narodowe 22 Lipca o dokonaniach PKWN. (VII 1947); 22) Odczyt mowy na temat sytuacji Polski na miedzynarodowej arenie politycznej (VII 1947); 23) Przemowienie na plenum Sejmu referujace ustawe o planie odbudowy gospodarczej. (VII 1947); 25) Referat na Komisje Planu Gospodarczego - Rolnictwo. (VII 1947).
  - 1947 (numbers 26-28) (Box-folder 1: 5)
    26) Analiza porownawcza komunistycznego i kapitalistycznego powojennego rozwoju gospodarczego. (Jesien 1947); 27) Przemowienie w Sejmie - Dyskusja nad budzetem. (VII 1947); 28) Referat w Sejmie o budzecie na rok 1948.
  - 1947 (numbers 29-36) (Box-folder 1: 6)
    29) Wytyczne dla przemowien w dniu Swieta Ludowego. (1947); 30) Polityka morska szerokiego oddechu. Artykul opublikowany w "Glosie Ludu". (VI 1946); 31) Na drodze rozwoju polskiego handlu zagranicznego. (Artykul opublikowany w "Trybunie Wolnosci• Nr.2 II 1947); 32) Historia odrodzenia demokratycznego panstwa polskiego. (I 1947); 33) Plan odbudowy gospodarczej. Artykul opublikowany w "Nowych Drogach". (Nr. 1, I 1947); 34) Niedzwiedzia przysluga. Krytyka emigracyjnego rzadu Mikolajczyka. Artykul opublikowany w "Glosie Ludu". (III 1945); 35) Przemowienie w Sejmie o przyjazni polsko-czechoslowackiej. (IV 1947); 36) Sprawy gospodarcze. Niektore zagadnienia gospodarki polskiej. (VII 1947).
  - 1948 (numbers 37-45) (Box-folder 1: 7)
    37) Dochod narodowy Polski w 1947 r. (1948); 38) Inwestycje na wybrzezu morskim w latach 1946 - 1948. (1948); 39) Zjednoczenie PPR i PPS. Problematyka zwiazkowa. (Relacja nagrana w KC PZPR 10 V 1988); 40) Glowne roznice zdan pomiedzy PPR a PPS. (Relacja nagrana w CA Kc PZPR 12 IV 1988); 41) Zjednoczenie PPR i PPS. (Relacja nagrana w CA KC PZP 12 IV 1988); 42) Wlochy w przededniu wyborow. (1988); 43) Obchody Rocznicy Rewolucji 1848. Artykul opublikowany w Articles et Documents. (1948); 44) Przemowa wygloszona na akademii z okazji setnej rocznicy Rewolucji Wegierskiej 1848 roku. (14.III.1948); 45) Przemowienie wygloszone na plenum Sejmu o ustawie o Narodowym Planie Gospodarczym nas rok 1948. (9 III 1948).
  - 1948 (numbers 46-51) (Box-folder 1: 8)
    46) Przemowienie wygloszone w trzecia rocznice smierci Franklina D. Roosevelta (12.IV.1948); 47) Planowanie gospodarcze jako zasada polskie'j gospodarki narodowej. Referat wygloszony na kursie planowania Centralnego Zwiazku Spoldzielczego w Otwocku. (21.VI.1948); 48) Planowanie w rybolostwie morskim. Referat wygloszony na naradzie rybackiej w Kolobrzegu. (VIII 1948); 49) Plan Marshalla. Artykul opublikowany w "Nowych Drogach." (IX 1948); 50) Referat o sytuacji gospodarczej kraju. (9.XI.1947); 51) Kryzys w kierownictwie PPR w 1948 roku. (16.III.1983).
  - 1949 (numbers 52-59) (Box-folder 1: 9)
    52) Przemowienie w Sejmie dotyczace dekretu o arbitrazu. (Jesien 1949); 53) Sprawozdanie z zebrania aktywu powiatowego powiatu radomskiego 20.11.1949 na temat uchwal III Plenum KC PZPR; 54) Sprawozdanie z narady partyjnego aktywu wiejskiego w powiecie gdanskim. (30.X.1949); 55) Artykul dla Trybuny Ludu dotyczacy polityki ekonomicznej. (XI.1949); 56) Sprawozdanie z zebrania organizacji podstawowych kolejarskich stacji Warszawa Zachodnia w warsztatach kolejowych w Szczeeliwicach w dniu 21.XI.1949, na temat uchwal III Plenum KC PZPR; 57) Referat na rocznice Rewolucji Pazdziernikowej. (5.XI.49); 58) Przemawianie wygloszone na Naradzie Oszczednosciowej w kwietniu 1949; 59) Niektore elementy wtornego podzialu dochodu narodowego w Polsce. Artykul "za Procznyj Mir i Narodnuju Demokracju." (1949).
  - 1950 (numbers 60-65 and one unnumbered speech) (Box-folder 1: 10)
    60) Referat o postepie technicznym w ramach planu szescioletniego i rozwoju szkolnictwa wyzszego. (1950); 61) Osiagniecia gospodarcze Polski Ludowej i reforma pieniezna. (XI 1950); 62) O planowaniu gospodarczym w terenie. Stenogram wykladu wygloszonego na kursie Sekretarzy Komitetow Powiatowych. (VII 1950); 63) Socjalistyczne planowanie i jego znaczenie polityczne. Referat Ministra Jedrychowskiego. (16.XI.1950); 64) Plan szescioletni. (1950); 65) Przemowienie w Sejmie na temat planu szkolenia zawodowego. (4.II.1950); unnumbered speech on Czechoslovakia and Poland relations.
  - 1950 (numbers 1-4) (Box-folder 1: 11)
  - 1950 (numbers 5-7) (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 1950 (numbers 8-13) (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - 1950 (numbers 14-16) (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1950 (numbers 17-21) (Box-folder 2: 2)
  - 1951 (numbers 22, 24-27, 29, 31?) (Box-folder 2: 3)
  - 1951 (numbers 70, 82?, 85, 87, 89) (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - 1952 (numbers 91?-93, 96-97, 99-100, and one unnumbered dated May 2) (Box-folder 2: 5)
  - 1952 (numbers 101, 107, 109, 113?, 115?, 117) (Box-folder 2: 6)
  - 1952 (numbers 118-120, 122) (Box-folder 2: 7)
  - 1952-1955 (numbers 124, 137, 142-143, and 5 unnumbered from or about 1953-1955) (Box-folder 2: 8)
  - Speech to comrades of the People's Republic of China, 1955 (Box-folder 2: 9)
  - Speech to comrades and citizens of the People's Republic of China, 1958 October (Box-folder 2: 10)
  - Interview with S. Jędrychowski in Głos Wybrzeża, 1961 March 22 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Speech to a meeting marking "Dnia Stoczniowca i Swięta Morza,", 1961 July 1 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - Typescript of interview with S. Jędrychowski published in Aušra, 1962 January 31 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Speech to Polish Sejm, 1962 November 29 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - Offprint of Jędrychowski's "Rozwój gospodarki narodowej w XX-leciu PRL,", 1964 May 14 (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Speech to Polish Sejm, 1964 November 16 (Box-folder 2: 16)
  - Notatka z rozmów między kierownictwem PZPR i KPZR, 1965 October 29-30 (Box-folder 2: 17)
    Participants include Władysław Gomułka, Józef Cyrankiewicz, Zenon Kliszko, Stefan Jędrychowski, L. I. Brezniew (Л. И. Брежнев), K. T. Mazurow (К. Т. Мазуров), J. W. Andropow (Ю. В. Андропов), W. N. Nowikow (В. Н. Новиков), P. M. Maszerow (П. М. Машеров), W. I. Kozłow (В.И. Козлов), T. D. Kisielew.
  - Typescript of interview of S. Jędrychowski by Grzegorz Sołtysiak, part 1, 1993 late?-1994 early? (Box-folder 2: 18)
  - Typescript of interview of S. Jędrychowski by Grzegorz Sołtysiak, part 2, 1994 February 17 (Box-folder 2: 19)
- Photographs, 1941-1989
  Nearly all photographs involve Jędrychowski as a participant in an official visit, social gathering, speech, tour, etc., often with foreign dignitaries. Based on the collection, it can be assumed that most of the images of factories, construction projects, etc. in which he does not appear are related to his personal visits in an official capacity or some aspect of his work in economic planning in Poland. Jędrychowski has made annotations on the back of nearly all of the photos, which seem to have mostly been taken by professional, official photographers. The scope and content notes accompanying each year are not exhaustive and represent a brief summary of the contents of each envelope. The verso of each photograph should be consulted for more detailed information. In the summary descriptions of each year when a subject is left out, such as “in conversation with X,” it can be assumed that it is Jędrychowski in conversation with X. However, in many of the official visit photographs Jędrychowski appears as a fellow marcher, listener, or observer of a signing and not as the main participant.
  There has been some water damage to the photographs in this collection
  The photographs have been arranged in three subseries by size: 7 x 5-inch photographs are arranged chronologically in Small photographs; photographs up to 12 x 8.5 inches are arranged chronologically in Large photographs; the largest items are stored in a flat box and in the subseries Oversize photographs.
  - Small photographs, 1941-1989
    - 1941 (Box 3)
      Saratov group photo of Polish and Ukrainian activists.
    - 1944 (Box 3)
      S.Jędrychowski portraits (one marked Moscow); group ceremony in woods with 3 faces scratched out; group ceremony on rostrum constructed of birch trees, icon of Christ attached to front of rostrum; 4 faces scratched out.
    - 1945 (Box 3)
      S.Jędrychowski portrait; 3 photos of processions; „Podpisanie umowy handlowej Polsko-Norweskiej w Warszawie” on 1945 August 29 with 4 Norwegian representatives and 5 Polish, including. Min. Jędrychowski; Lublin on 1945 October 12 „W dniu pobytu p. Ministera Żeglugi i Handlu Zagranicznego”; „Podpisanie umowy handlowej Polsko-Duńskiej w Warszawie” on 1945 August 29.
    - 1946 (Box 3)
      Group photos in Belgrade, Prague, Szczecin, Västerås (Sweden), Gdańsk factories and waterfront; „Dalmor” Gdynia on 1946 May 2; „Podpisanie umowy handlowej Bułgarsko-Polskiej” on 1946 April 30; „Narada Ryubacka” 1946 November.
    - 1947 (Box 3)
      Minister Żeglugi i Handlu Zagranicznego with staff in 1947 July.
    - 1948 (Box 3)
      Budapest signing ceremony.
    - 1950 (Box 3)
      S.Jędrychowski portrait; group photo in Czechoslovakia; speaking in Budapest.
    - 1952 (Box 3)
      Premier Bolesław Bierut, Jozef Cyrankiewicz, Hilary Minc.
    - 1954 (Box 3)
      Group photos in Moscow and Poznań; rally in Poznań; on the water in China; Wrocław in 1954 August.
    - 1955 (Box 3)
      Military review on 10th anniversary of 4 April 1945.
    - 1957 (Box 3)
      3 photos of ceremonies in Gdańsk.
    - 1958 (Box 3)
      Group photos in Moscow, Gdańsk, Krakow, Warsaw and other Polish towns and country side; delegate card for IV kongres związków zawodowych; Bucharest.
    - 1959 (Box 3)
      Group photos in Leszno, Starachowice and a close-up of S. J. with Gomułka, Cyrankiewicz and one other; pilots group; Związek spółdzielni mieszkaniowych, Warszawa on 1959 April 25-26.
    - 1960 (Box 3)
      Poznań ceremony with Askanas, Gomułka, Cyrankiewicz and one other; signing ceremony in Warsaw with Soviet Union, 1960 March 10; small group photos in Hungary, Polish countryside, planning committee meeting, Lubin site visit; multiple photos of Wrocław factory visit.
    - 1961 (Box 3)
      Vietnamese minister Nguyễn Duy Trinh visit; Gdańsk; with Soviet Deputy Premier Novikov; Brno visit; Komisja sejmowa; in Morskie Oko; visit to the Gdańsk Polytechnic.
    - 1962 (Box 3)
      XLIV Liceum Ogólnokształcące im. A. Dobiszewskiego.
    - 1963 (Box 3)
      Gdańsk rostrum view of XXVIII Mistrzostwa Świata w Szermierce; Gorlice construction site visit; Łódź factory visit; 3 photos formerly mounted on black sheet „Zwiedzanie prototypu pierwszej wiertnicy do głebokich wierceń typ wos 2000 konstrukcji fabryki Maszyn 'Glinik'.”
    - 1964 (Box 3)
      Tour of Zeiss factory, Jena; group photo, Hungary mountaintop; in a march; Dubrovnik, Yugoslavia on 1964 September 13; receiving award on 1964 July 18.
    - 1965 (Box 3)
      Poznań in 1965 June; Szczecin in 1965 June.
    - 1966 (Box 3)
      Gdańsk factory; Budapest International Fair; group photos at other Polish factories; speaking to a delegation of industrialists (some from America); in Rome at archeological site.
    - 1967 (Box 3)
      In German Democratic Republic on 1967 January 27; „Uroczystość rozruchu I etapu ZCP Swiecie n/Wisła” on 1967 October 28; in Budapest.
    - 1968 (Box 3)
      Meeting with army; with a model at the Archeological Museum in Warsaw; at XXXVIIth International Fair, Poznań; other exhibit visits in Warsaw and elsewhere.
    - 1969 (Box 3)
      Soviet Union; Syria; other travel and delegations; diplomatic evening function; tour in Samarkand; other travel in Soviet Union; Łańsk with other government ministers; evening reception in Archeological Museum, Warsaw.
    - 1970 (Box 3)
      Visit of Turkish ambassador; UN delegation card as Chairman of the Polish Delegation; with Turkish foreign minister at reception and on ship; signing protocol with Turkish minister Cermik; COMECON-related parade of dignitaries.
    - 1971 (Box 3)
      Discussion at UN; in Japan.
    - 1972 (Box 3)
      5 Warsaw-based photos as Minister of Finance.
    - 1973 (Box 3)
      Polish factory visit; engaging in party volunteer work (shovelling) in Warsaw; signing a protocol; Minister of Finance-related meetings in Warsaw and Katowice; signing ceremony at COMECON in Budapest; at Zlatni Pyasatsi (Златни пясъци), Bulgaria.
    - 1974 (Box 3)
      As Finance Minister; party work in the field; speaking in Poznań; COMECON in Ciechocinek in 1974 May.
    - 1975 (Box 3)
      Budapest; on a camel in Ulan Bator at COMECON function; contract signing in Budapest on 1976 May 20; in Győr.
    - 1976 (Box 3)
      Meeting French minister; in Bristol with Iranian ambassador; group photos in Poland; at conference; in Békéscsaba.
    - 1977 (Box 3)
      Budapest school visit and other events.
    - 1980-1984 (Box 3)
      In Soviet Union in 1980; in Warsaw with Chinese visitor, Wang Bing N[?] on 1984 April 16.
    - 1987-1989 (Box 3)
      COMECON in Vilnius on 1987 October 16; „45 lech I Warszawskiej Dywizji im Tadeusza Kosciuszki”; January 2 at table.
    - No date, miscellaneous (Box 3)
  - Large photographs, 1944-1988
    - 1944 (Box 4)
      „Przedstawsiele Krajowej Rady narodowej gośemi I. Armii Polskiej w ZSRR” 1944 May.
    - 1945 (Box 4)
      „I Zjazd Hubników w Polsce, Katowice” 1945 July 28-29.
    - 1946 (Box 4)
      With Minister Dr. L. Grosfeld in conversation with UNRRA representatives Mr. E. Hays and Mr. E. A. Mills, 1946 January 9.
    - 1947 (Box 4)
      „Wystawa budownicza” Moscow, 1947 November; „Komitet Slowianski” 1947 November; „Gen. Gundorow” Moscow, 1947 November.
    - 1948 (Box 4)
      As a delegate of the Polish Workers’ Party to the VI Congresso, Milan 1948 January 4-10.
    - 1954 (Box 4)
      6 photographs of official visit to China in 1954 October; acknowledging Polish troops, 1954 May 9.
    - 1958 (Box 4)
      Gdańsk factory visit; „Uroczyste przekazanie odkrywki Gostawice do eksploatacji” 1958 August 31.
    - 1959 (Box 4)
      Gomułka in conversation at the 21st Communist Party Congress of the Soviet Union in Moscow, 1958 January; Polish Worker’s Party delegation at the 21st Communist Party congress of the Soviet Union in Moscow, 1958 January; in conversation with Ralph J. Bunche on 1959 August 18; speaking at Kielce factory in 1959 February.
    - 1960 (Box 4)
      With Kosygin and Patolichev in Moscow on 1960 February 11; in Indonesia on 1960 August 11; with Chinese delegation, including vice premier.
    - 1961 (Box 4)
      15 photographs of trip to Peking in 1961 September-October; Gdańsk factory visit on 1961 June 2; Gdańsk official meal on 1961 July 1; Poznań trade fair on 1961 June 6; IV Kongres techników Polskich in Wrocław, 1961 February 12; at Gdańsk factory with Soviet ambassador Averkii Borisovich Aristov (Аверкий Борисович Аристов).
    - 1962 (Box 4)
      „Stopien wodny we Włocławku, założenie aktu erekcyjnego” on 1962 April 28; Gdańsk 1000-year commemoration on 1962 July 22.
    - 1963 (Box 4)
      Reviewing troops on 1963 September 15; XXVIII mistrzostwa świata w szermierce in Gdańsk, 1963 July 17-28; factory ceremony on 1963 December 23.
    - 1964 (Box 4)
      Electrical power station; signing a document in Sofia on 1964 December 17.
    - 1965 (Box 4)
      Most portowy, budowa 1963-1965, Szczecin – otwarcie, 1965 November 11.
    - 1966 (Box 4)
      In front of a refinery model at ENI’s research facility in San Donato, 1966 June 25; at ENI refinery in Gela, 1966 June 25; May Day celebration in Szczecin.
    - 1967 (Box 4)
      In Stockholm 1967 April 4; at Olsztyn factory 1967 August 28; meeting Mauno Koivisto on 1967 May 4; „Widok na Główny Blok Celulozy” 1967 November; reviewing AEI literature connected to the 36th Poznan International Fair (in London?) 1967 July 4.
    - 1968 (Box 4)
      Clipping of photograph published in Great Britain of Poland’s political bureau and secretariat taken at the V Party Congress; with Jaruzelski at monument to the Bitwa pod Cedyni; with American(?) diplomat at a reception on 1968 August 4; in Katowice on 1968 November 8 [heavily damaged by water].
    - 1969 (Box 4)
      4 photographs in Algeria, 1969 April 25-29; with the Soviet Minister of Foreign Affairs in Moscow on 1969 February 28.
    - 1970 (Box 4)
      4 photographs at the UN in New York, 1 with Nixon, 1 with Gromyko; 5 photographs of trip to France in 1970 May.
    - 1971 (Box 4)
      4 photographs in Berlin, 1971 January; with American ambassador; in Japan, 1971 April; with Janos Kadar in 1971 May; at the Polish embassy in Budapest with the Soviet and Polish ambassadors; with the Hungarian foreign minister Janos Peter.
    - 1972 (Box 4)
      At COMECON meeting in Budapest, 1972 May 8-11; as Minister of Finance.
    - 1973 (Box 4)